# MATTHEW MANGAN

East Rochester, NY 14445 | 315.719.2541 | matt@mangan.io

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Full stack web developer with a passion for lightning fast and A11y compliant websites. Highly skilled in creating a tailored WordPress environment from the ground up to ensure the best possible experience for internal and external users.

#### SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Languages: HTML5 | JS/JQuery | PHP | CSS/SCSS | React | MySQL
- Software & Tools: Adobe Suite | JIRA | WordPress | Git | VSCode

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **UX Developer - Excellus BCBS**

06/2018 - Current

Rochester, NY

- Design, code and implement online user interfaces for websites, web applications, and mobile applications in an AGILE development cycle.
- Write scalable and cross-browser compatible code within enterprise-level CMS that adheres to WC3/A11y and departmental web design/usability standards.
- Maintain high regard for member privacy in accordance with the corporate privacy policies and procedures.

## Owner - Manganite Consulting

06/2015 - Current

Rochester, NY

- Create SEO optimized and responsive B2B, B2C, and e-commerce sites.
- Meet and correspond with clients in person to determine needs for company sites and to ensure product deliverables are of the highest standard.
- Manage client acquisition, proposals, and contracts from start to finish.

# Web Developer – Mason Marketing

04/2016 - 05/2018

Penfield, NY

- Led development practices regarding the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA/A11y) to make websites fully accessible to everyone.
- Increased site load speed by up to 50% across all projects.
- Created customized, reusable WordPress template to decrease site programming time by 25% for each developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

SUNY Brockport – B.S. Computer Information Systems – 2013